你到底在医务室里干什么?
What you're doing in the infirmary,
那跟咱们做的有什么联系?
what's it gotta do with here?
四天后的晚上  咱们就能离开这里了
Four days from now,on the night of the escape,
我们有18分钟的 时间从医务室逃走
we'll have 18 minutes to get the bars off the window
一共7个人将爬过电线
and for all seven of us to get across the wire
越过高墙
and over the wall.
-可能么?  -当然
-Is that doable?  -Of course.
玛丽克鲁兹  是我 亲爱的  到底出了什么事?
Maricruz, what the hell is going on?
赫克托说你可以慢慢享受牢狱生活
Yeah, well, Hector says you can serve your full sentence.
你来这儿干嘛? 玛丽克鲁兹呢?
What are you doing here?where is Maricruz
她再也不会来了
She's not gonna be coming around here any more.
你在和我开玩笑?
It's ajoke, right?
她现在跟我了
She's with me now.
我只是想知道
I just need to know
迈克尔·斯科菲尔德 为什么要为你换取绿卡?
what Michael Scofield wanted from you in exchange for the green card.
在监狱里你要绿卡有什么用?
Why would you need a credit card in prison?
如果我知道事情会 发展到现在这个地步的话
If I'd known how this was gonna turn out,
我宁愿去捡联邦人员的烂摊子
I'd have gotten some crap job with the Feds.
你再说下去我就把子弹放到你脑袋里
Keep talking like that,I'm gonna put a bullet in your head.
我必须出去
I need to get out
我还有我的生活
while I still got my life.
爸爸! 爸爸!
Daddy! Daddy!
事情变了
Things have changed.
我想加入
I want in.
怎么了?
So?
咱们人太多了
We've got too many people.
我算了一下  他们中必须有一个人放弃
I've done the math. One of 'em has to go.
抱歉让您久等
Sorry to keep you waiting.
没有关系
Oh, it's not a problem.
很不错的简历
Impressive resume.
多谢
Thank you.
告诉我你为什么选择 继续在工程领域发展
Tell me why you chose to pursue a career in engineering.
是这样的
Well, um...
我一直对结构和几何学比较感兴趣
I've always been interested in structure.Geometry.
(还有)物体是怎样结合在一起的
How things fit together.
建筑物功能的展现...
How an object that performs a function
同样也应该算作艺术
can also be a work of art.
你的未来是怎么打算的?
What about the future?
你认为5年后你会变成什么样?
Where do you see yourself in five years?
一套制服  黑色
One suit, black.
那个小男孩长大了么?
That baby boy all growed up yet?
再过几年他就会闹的天翻地覆了
Oh, he's gonna raise hell the next few years.
就像他妈妈那样
Take after his momma.
是的  和过去差不多
Yeah, you know. Same old same up here.
但是  嗯...
But, uh...
情况有些不妙
things are getting pretty tense.
比如冲突啊什么的
Like they're fixing to, uh... collide.
了解我的意思么  吉米?
You know what I mean, Jimmy?
可能会...
There's a potential situation.
我找到进入医务室的办法了
I found our access to the infirmary.
但我需要些时间来运作
I'm gonna need time to make it work.
需要多久?
How much time?
足够找出不用梯子就能从 20英尺深的排水管道里上去的方法
Enough for me to find my way up a 20 ft vertical drainpipe without using a ladder.
明天的狱工我去不了了
I'll probably need to skip PI tomorrow
如果我想把事情完成的话
if I wanna get this thing done.
不能不去
You can't just skip it.
这不像是上学
It ain't class.
如果狱警突然来了怎么办?
What if one of the bulls decides to drop in?
我已别无选择了  不是么?
I don't have a choice, do I?
只要我们能打通警卫室的管道
Once we get through the pipe below the guards' room
剩下的事就容易多了
it'll be easier.
我不通过门就能到达各处
I can come and go without using the door,
韦斯特莫兰德为咱们放哨
and with Westmoreland as lookout,
还要再加个人来帮忙挖掘
we'll have one more man for digging.
韦斯特莫兰德可不是省油的灯
He's a problem.
咱们7个人要想爬过那墙根本不可能
All seven of us can't break over that wall in 18 minutes.
你自己也说了  根本不可能
You said it yourself. It's impossible.
兄弟我告诉你 咱们必须要甩掉一个人
Listen, man, one of us has gotta take a hike.
我知道
I know.
介意告诉我你们在谈什么么?
Mind if I share that with the rest of the class?
很显然  大学生已经计算过
Apparently, college boy here did the math.
我们的"车"已经超载了
Figured out that we got too many clowns in the car.
也就是说虽然咱们都在这里挖洞
So one of us is in here digging,
但最后却有个人连座位都落不着
but his seat ain't guaranteed.
你有什么意见么  伙计?
How's this your problem?
他根本就不知道自己在说什么
He doesn't know what he's talking about.
要是不带我出去  我就不挖了
I won't dig if I'm not gonna go.
我们必须决定不带谁
We need to decide who gets cut.
这个大家心里早就有数了  对么?
I think we all can agree who that should be,right?
噢  不好意思打扰你们了
Pardon me for interrupting,
但是  呃...
but, uh...
这像是什么?
what's that smell?
我闻到了阴谋的气味
It smells a little like conspiracy.
我们必须抓紧干活了
We need to get back to work.
在此之前  我有话要说
I have an announcement to make.
我发觉我越来越被你们忽视了
I've been growing leery of the way you all talk like I'm a lesser man,
于是我就买了一份保单
so I bought an insurance policy.
我和外面的兄弟通了电话 并把咱们的计划告诉了他
I called up my guy on the outside and I told him about our plan,
我告诉他  如果可能 下周就能见到他了
and I told him in all likelihood I'll be seeing him next week.
但是...
But...
如果在逃走前5分钟或是成功后 20分钟还收不到我的消息的话
if he don't hear from me five minutes before the escape and 20 minutes after,
他就会给监狱打电话 告诉他们全部的事情
I told him to call up the warden, blow the whistle on the whole thing.
所以如果你们已经想好了如何对付我的话
So if y'all got ideas about getting rid of me,
我建议你们还是想想其他办法吧
I suggest you make other plans.
那狗日的到处和我们作对
Son of a bitch has got a countermove for everything.
这次不会了
Not for this.
谁会被踢出  我还是你
Odd men out. Me and you.
什么意思?
What do you mean?
看你现在和谁在一起
Look who you're walking with right now.
你本应该和他们步调一致的
You should be up there,
一起安排怎么逃出去
calling the shots with the rest of the suits.
-没错  那又怎么样?   -怎么样...
-Yeah? So?  -So.
斯科菲尔德来这儿只有一个目的
Scofield is only here for one reason.
就是他哥哥
His brother.
他只需要两样东西
And he only needs two things.
老头的钱  还有土匪头子的飞机
The old man's money, and the mob boss's plane.
他根本用不着你
He don't need you.
你只不过是碰巧和他一个牢房而已
You just happened to be in the same cell when he got here.
你和厕所
You and the toilet.
我为此做了很多
I've done a lot of work on this thing.
我又何尝不是呢
Exactly. Me too.
咱们都是给人家当苦力的
We're just the labourers on this thing, man.
真到该逃出去的时候
The night that fish goes into that hole,
你真的认为他会带上这么多累赘么?
you think he wants all that extra baggage?
这就是咱们
Cos that's all we are.
我不管你要怎样  我要走了
I don't know about you, but I'm going.
他到底告诉了你多少呢?
How much does he tell you, anyways?
还是只有他一个人知道?
Or does he keep it all to himself?
他肯定会说  你知道的越少越少  对么?
Yeah, he probably tells you the less you know the better, right?
你根本什么都不知道
You don't know what you're talking about.
他什么都告诉我了
He tells me everything.
他要真都告诉你了  那你就不需要他了
If he tells you everything, then you don't need him.
咱们可以自己逃出去  我和你
Now, we can go by ourselves. Me and you.
或者你可以等
Or, you know, you can wait, and see
然后看看斯科菲尔德到底 愿不愿意带上闲杂人等
if Scofield really wants to carry a heavy weight.
你决定吧  伙计
It's up to you, papi.
嘿  我还等着呢
Yo. I'm still waiting.
在等什么?
What for?
我帮你搞定了那块手表 我的工作呢?
I swiped you that watch, man. Where's my PI?
根本不可能
That's not gonna happen.
你答应过我
You promised.
我说我会考虑  或许在不远的将来
I said I'd think about it. Maybe somewhere down the road.
我才不信你的鬼话呢
Yeah, I ain't gonna hold my breath.
那我该怎么做?
What do you want me to do?
快去找人! 快去!
Get somebody.
不  不  不! 不要  他们看到子弹肯定会报警的
No, no, they see a bullet, they're gonna call the cops.
这不是没办法了么? 我是不会让你死的
We don't have a choice! I'm not gonna let you die.
找到它!
Find it.
什么?
What?
子弹  找到它然后挖出来
The bullet. Just find it and dig it out.
我办不到  -照我说的做!
I can't.  -Do it!
斯科菲尔德呢?
Where's Scofield?
原来在这儿
There you are.
刚去牢房找过你  哪儿都找不到你
Just looked for you in your cell. Couldn't find you anyplace.
当然  也没发现你的信用卡
Couldn't find your credit card either.
你明白我的意思
You know the one I'm talking about.
就是你那个当鸡的老婆 前几天偷着带进来的那张
The one your whore wife trunked in the other day.
她都告诉我了
She told me all about it.
或许妓女很厉害吧
Maybe "whore" is too strong.
你是怎么把一个嫁给 重罪犯的女孩弄到美国来的呢?
What do you call a girl who married a felon to get into the United States?
她来这里的目的又是什么呢?
Why'd she have to come here, anyway?
Whazistan没有脱衣俱乐部?
No strip clubs in Whazitstan?
-贝利克警官  -是警长
-Officer Bellick...  -Captain.
好  能否在别的时间进行您的审问呢?
Fine. Do you mind conducting your inquisitions on your own time?
我可没那么多的时间
I've a schedule to maintain.
不好意思  医生
Excuse me, Doctor.
我只是想问问斯科菲尔德 先生关于违禁品的事情
I was just asking Mr Scofield about the contraband
他的脱衣舞老婆那天带进来的
he had his stripper wife trunk in the other day.
你先忙你的  你的工作更重要
But you go ahead. Your job's more important.
自从我进来那天他就和我过不去
He's had it out for me since the day I got here.
-不要动  -不好意思
-Hold still, please.  -Sorry.
我和她结婚...
I only married her
这样她才能拿到绿卡
so she could get her green card.
我看到你们从夫妻间里出来了
I saw you coming out of the conjugal room.
不过是场交易罢了
That's just business.
迈克尔  你没必要跟我解释这些
You don't have to explain it to me, Michael.
我知道
I know.
我觉得有必要说
But I want to.
大盗?
DB. Oh,
你还真成大盗了? 我一直以为你只是个牛仔呢
is that who you is now? I thought you was just a cowboy.
离我远点  臭小子
Take a couple of steps back, boy.
有件事我一直想不明白
What I can't understand
你都这把年纪了竟然还想出去
is why somebody like you wants to get out anyway.
出去后怎么生存呢?
How you gonna survive, huh?
世界变了  变得很恐怖...
The world's all different now. It's scary.
人家都用电脑打电话  用硅胶隆胸
They got computer phones, boobies made of silicone.
你什么都不会做
You wouldn't know what to do.
我没必要向你证明什么
I don't have to justify myself to you.
不  你必须要证明一下
Oh, you're gonna have to.
否则这把老骨头会拖我们后腿的
Them old bones is gonna be dragging us down.
或许我现在就折断几根试试
Maybe I'll just snap a few right now...
你尽管来
Take your best shot.
嘿  你们是怎么回事!
Hey, break it up down there!
退出吧  牛仔 我不会再警告你的
Bow out, cowboy. I'm not gonna warn you no more.
什么事?
What's up?
院子里电话的记录 詹姆斯·博格威尔  住在加里市区
Records from the phone in the yard. James Bagwell lives down in Gary.
帝博格所谓的保单?
T-Bag's insurance policy?
没错
Yeah.
我的人会暂时把他们关在货车里 直到咱们安全以后
My guy's gonna lock him up in a moving van for a couple of days until we're in the clear.
-货车?  -是的
-Moving van?  -Yeah.
放心  不会有事的 我们经常这样做的
Don't worry. He can breathe, and all. We do it all the time.
那帝博格呢?
What about T-Bag?
他不再是威胁了  相信我
He's no longer a threat. Trust me.
您是詹姆斯·博格威尔么? 有您的邮包
You James Bagwell? Got a delivery for you.
-是吗?  -是的
-Yeah?  -Yeah.
-你没事吧?  -没事
-You all right?  -Yeah.
-太太?  -什么事?
-Ma'am?  -Yes?
能和您说两句话么?
Can I speak with you, please?
当然可以 待在这儿别动  好么?
Of course.You stay here, OK?
他还好吧?
Is he gonna be OK?
我们现在还不知道  他失血过多
We don't know yet.
我本打算给警察打电话的 但我还是想先和你谈谈
I was gonna call the police,I wanted to speak with you first.
他的伤很显然是枪伤
His wound is obviously the product of a gunshot.
你最好对我说实话
You need to be honest with me.
枪伤到底是怎么来的?
What was he doing when he got shot?
他当时在车库里  在车子的下面
He was in the garage, underneath his car.
他现在还在急诊室
He's in surgery right now.
失血已经导致他的肌肉组织缺氧
The blood loss has caused his muscle tissue to suffer from a lack of oxygen.
他的肩膀也受到相同程度的损伤
He's sustained damage to his shoulder.
而且体内的子弹还未取出 感染的几率也会随之升高
With a bullet there's an increased risk of infection.
所以还得早点确定下来的好
So he has to be admitted.
需要给什么人打电话么?  家人什么的?
Is there anyone you should call? Family?
不  只有我一个
No. It's just me.
那么  好吧... 有什么情况我会尽快通知你的
All right. Well, I'll let you know as soon as he's in recovery.
谢谢
Thank you.
喂
Yeah?
-你到了么?  -快了
-Are you there yet?  -Almost.
切记  一定要耐心 跟着他
Remember. Be patient, follow his lead.
咱们今天要一箭三雕
We want the trifecta today.
好的  我这就去
Yeah, I'm on it.
是我
It's me.
我有个坏消息给你
Yeah, I got bad news.
有多坏?
Yeah? Like what?
你要求的事被我办砸了
The job you ordered went bad.
那家伙是个妄想狂  还有把枪
The guy was paranoid, he had a gun.
然后就
One thing led to another.
什么  他死了?
What? He's dead?
是的  更不幸的是...
Yeah. And unfortunately...
还有个孩子
there was a kid there.
你到底是怎么回事? 你竟然对一个孩子下手?
What are you... What are you talking about?You killed a kid?
我是无意的
It was unintentional.
-只是个孩子  伙计  -我知道  我很抱歉
-It's a kid, man.  -I know. I'm sorry.
他竟然用孩子当挡箭牌
SOB used him as a shield.
-男孩还是女孩?  -好像是个男孩
-Boy or a girl?  -I don't know. A boy.
-多大?  -四岁或五岁的样子
-How old?  -Four, maybe five.
-谁要见我?  -我怎么会知道  一位女士
-Who's here to see me?  -Hell if I know. Some lady.
亲爱的
Baby.
嗨
Hi.
你看起来真漂亮
You look so beautiful.
我来是想要告诉你一下
I came here cos I have to tell you something.
什么?
What?
我怀孕了  费尔南多
I'm pregnant, Fernando.
怀孕?
Pregnant?
怀的是你的孩子
With your baby.
我将要生下你的儿子了
I'm gonna have your son.
你... 你马上就要...
You... You're gonna...
我们...
We...
我们即将有自己的孩子了?
We're gonna have a baby?
嘿  伙计  你听见了么? 我就要当爸爸了!
Oye, papi, you hear that? I'm gonna be a dad!
-我还没说完呢!  -什么  妈咪  什么?
-I'm not finished.  -What, mami? What?
好的  是赫克托... 他向我求婚了
OK. Hector, he asked me to marry him.
什么?
What?
-我也知道这听起来有点疯狂  -那就拒绝他啊
-Look, it's crazy, I know.  -Tell him no.
告诉他你怀了我的孩子 我们就要拥有自己的家庭了
Tell him you're having my son. We'll be a family.
费尔南多... 我妈妈说...
Fernando, look.My mom,
抚养一个孩子是世界上最难的事情
she says that having a baby is the hardest job in the whole world.
而且再让我一个人来抚养 更是难上加难
And it's even harder if I do this by myself.
我现在只知道我害怕极了
And all I know is, I'm really scared.
我真的害怕自己一人来承担
I'm really scared to do this alone.
你不必如此的
You won't have to.
我还没有拒绝他
Well, I haven't told him no yet.
等一下  等一下
Wait, wait.
你根本没有仔细想过
You're not actually considering this?
亲爱的... 我不知道  我不知道
Oh, baby. I don't know. I don't know.
天哪  亲爱的 你不能总听信别人的
My God, baby, you gotta stop listening to these people.
他们在毒害你的思想
They're poisoning your brain.
你的荷尔蒙使你变得不正常了 你根本不曾好好考虑过
Your hormone things are out of whack. You're not thinking straight.
咱们说的可是咱们自己的孩子
This is our child we're talking about.
你要相信我
I want you to listen to me.
等我出去
I want you to wait.
会有那一天的
I'm gonna be out.
比你想象的要快
Sooner than you think.
你一直都这么说
You keep on telling me that.
好啦  探视时间到  都回去吧
All right. Visiting time is up. Let's go.
告诉我你会等我的
Tell me you're gonna wait.
把手拿开  苏克雷!
Hands off, Sucre.
你的我的全部 亲爱的  不要这样
You're all I got left in the world, baby.Please.
我爱你
I love you.
但你会继续学着怎样去爱的  对么?
But you'll learn to love again, right?
亲爱的  告诉我你不会答应他的
Tell me you're gonna tell him no, honey.
我不知道 我什么都不知道
I don't know.I don't know anything any more.
苏克雷  走吧
Sucre. Come on.
-孩子到了  -非常好
-The kid's here.  -Perfect.
跟他到律师那里  然后再打给我
Follow him back to the lawyers, call me back.
你要去哪儿?
Where you going?
我十分钟后回来
I'll be back in ten minutes.
你要去做什么?
What do you have to do?
太复杂了  来不急解释
It's complicated. I can't explain.
不过如果成功的话...
But if it works,
你很快就会知道的
you'll see soon enough.
我要和你一起去  我现在就想知道
I want to go with you. I want to see now.
必须要有人留在这里
Someone has to stay here.
需要有人放哨的
I need a lookout.
每次都是我放哨
I'm always on lookout.
你是我的狱友 还怎么能是别人呢?
You're my cell mate.Who else is gonna do it?
10分钟后就回来  好么?
I'll be back in ten minutes. OK?
好吧
OK.
明天的事都准备好了 你想怎样处置他?
We're all lined up for tomorrow.Where do you want him?
约翰?
John.
明天你想让 帝博格怎样 在商店里还是工棚里?
Tomorrow.Where do you want T-Bag?In the shop or in the shed?
嘘...
Shh.
随便
I don't care.
你决定吧
You decide.
谢天谢地  你还好么?
Thank God.Are you OK?
是的  我没事
Yeah. I'm OK.
她什么都没做
She didn't do anything.
这不是她应得的
She didn't deserve it.
我知道
I know.
-给你  伙计  -好的  好的
-Here you go, man.  -Yeah.
把这些弄到手真不容易
These were seriously hard to get.
-你要这个有什么用?  -不关你事
-What you need 'em for, anyway?  -None of your business.
很感谢你能等我  图多尔
Thank you for waiting, Theodore.
我并非有意剥夺你的活动时间
I don't mean to deny your time in the yard.
到底什么事?
What's this all about?
嗯...
I, uh...
恐怕是些不好的消息
I'm afraid I have some terrible news.
你的堂兄詹姆斯昨天在家被枪杀了
Your cousin, James,was shot and killed in his home yesterday.
他的儿子小詹姆斯  也未能幸免
His son, James Junior, was killed as well.
我非常抱歉
I'm very, very sorry.
到底是什么意思?
What does it mean?
我的选择?
Am I chosen?
还是别的什么?
Or what?
上帝总能在你想要忏悔的时候出现
Often, the Lord appears when you're in particular need of forgiveness.
或许正如现在所发生的
Maybe that's what's happening right now.
约翰  现在还不晚
John, it's never too late.
你若愿意让神将罪恶驱除出你身
If you agree to accept Christ into your heart,and turn from your sin,
神将会宽恕并救你于永生
he will forgive you, and save you in eternity.
你认为呢?
Do you agree?
启事录  第三章  第20篇
Revelation, chapter three, verse 20.
主说 "看  我站在门外叩门
"Jesus said, 'Behold, I stand at the door and knock."'
若有听见我的声音就开门
"'Lf any man hear my voice and open the door,
我要进到他那里去"
I will come in to him."'
他昨晚去了医务室的那幢楼
He got to the infirmary building last night,
通过老下水道
through the old sewer pipe.
就是警卫室下面的管道
It's the same pipe that runs under the guards' room.
我就知道这么多
That's all I know.
就是那个小混蛋偷了我的手表
There's the little thumbsucker that swiped my watch.
谁? 那个双性恋?
Who? Tweener?
纯金的  说没就没了
Solid gold.Took it off my arm.
事后半小时我才发现
It was a half hour before I noticed.
这表原本是属于谁的?
Whose was it in the first place?
我对你偷的东西不感兴趣
I don't care if you stole it. You can tell me.
迈克尔·斯科菲尔德
Michael Scofield.
你在看什么?
What are you looking at?
一会儿拐角处见
I'll be right around the corner.
韦斯特莫兰德!
Westmoreland.
你吓了我一跳  长官
You scared me, boss.
赶紧干活去
Get back to work.
好吧  我们走!
All right, let's go.
抓紧点  斯科菲尔德
Move it, Scofield.
"要是我的话  我会求助于上帝 主会拯救我的
"For me, I would call upon God, and the Lord shall save me..."
我大声呼喊  他就会听到我的声音
"...cry aloud, and he shall hear my voice..."
他即将听到我的心声 他即将听到我的心声
"...he shall hear my voice... hear my voice..."
他即将听到我的心声
"...he shall hear my voice..."
"...hear my voice..."
你干什么呢?
What are you doing?
没事
Nothing.
帮我看着点  好么?
Well, keep an eye on the tier for me, will you?
咱们到底什么时候才能离开这儿?
When are we getting out of here, exactly?
我有权知道时间
I need to know the time.
就快了
As soon as possible.
"就快了" 可不是一个具体的时间
That's not a idiographic time.
-你告诉阿布鲁奇时间了么?  -当然  因为他必须知道
-You tell Abruzzi the time?  -He needs to know.
为什么他就必须知道而我却不能?
Why does he need to know and I don't?
因为他要安排飞机的时间 你怎么对什么都这么好奇了?
Because he's arranging the plane.Why the sudden curiosity?
你为什么非要知道那些 会给你带来危险的信息呢?
Why would you want to be responsible for potentially dangerous information?
你知道的越少越好
The less you know, the better.
这也是为了你好
It's for your own good.
我必须走了  做狱工的时候见
I have to go. I'll meet you in PI.
偷警卫的东西
Stealing from a guard.
你很可能会因此被关禁闭的
You could get thrown in the SHU for that.
或许再给你增加几年的刑期
Maybe even add a few years to your bit.
我也不知道...
I don't know what...
别解释  我什么都知道
No, don't deny it. I already know it's true.
幸运的是  我可以帮你
Lucky for you, I got some pull around here.
我可以帮你摆脱一切 就像从未发生过一样
I can make this sort of thing go away,like it never even happened.
真好吃
That's good.
现在...
Now...
我相信你也听说过 "卑鄙小人"
I'm sure you've heard the word "rat".
我也不喜欢告密者
I don't like it."Snitch", neither.
我不想让你做那种人
Those sort of words aren't appropriate for what I need from you.
我只是想了解一点点信息而已
What I need is a little information.
比如你和斯科菲尔德的交易...
Like when you're hanging out with Scofield...
你只要告诉我他都说了些什么
Just come back and tell me what he said.
我还有一个汉堡 可惜  老兄  我已经饱了
I got an extra burger.But, man, I'm full.
你说呢  老兄? 要不要来个干酪汉堡?
So what do you say, kiddo? Want a cheeseburger?
还是你想被关禁闭?
Or you want to go to the SHU?
这就对了
That's my boy.
嘿  亲爱的 你在这儿干什么呢?
Hey, honey, what are you doing here?
还以为你走了呢
I thought you left.
出什么事了?
What's wrong?
我  呃...我在想一件事情
I, um...I been thinking.
我想改变一下咱们的生活
I think we need to make a change.
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
还记得咱们刚结婚的时候么 当时说要搬往西部去住?
When we got married, we thought about moving out west.
没错  当时咱们才22岁
Yeah, we were 22.
或许咱们现在可以尝试一下 还不算太晚
Well, maybe we should give it a shot. It's not too late.
我不明白  到底出了什么事?
I don't understand. What brought this on?
工作上的事
It's just work.
我厌倦了整天在外面替别人卖命
I'm tired of being on the road working for somebody else
而你却每天都在家独自一人
while you sit at home all alone night after night.
我想过真正属于我们两个的生活
I want our lives to be about us.
我也是  但不能不考虑孩子和房子吧
I do too. But there's so much to think about, with the kids and the house.
我们一定要走
We gotta go.
你有麻烦了  对么?
You're in trouble, aren't you?
哦
Oh.
今天显得格外冷清啊
Crowd has thinned out in here.
弄得怎么样了  苏克雷?
How you doing, Sucre?
快好了  谁替一下我
Almost there. Switch me out.
换你了  然后是韦斯特莫兰德
You're up. Then Westmoreland.
一定要尽快挖通 迈克尔要从这里回来
We gotta get through, Michael's gonna be coming back this way.
您好? 维罗妮卡·多诺万?
Hello? Veronica Donovan?
你是哪位?
Who is this?
我是谁并不重要  别挂电话
I... It doesn't matter who I am. Don't hang up.
我了解一些事情  你可能会感兴趣
I have information that you may be interested in.
一些可以替林肯·布伦斯摆脱罪名的信息
Information that will lead to the exoneration of Lincoln Burrows.
什么? 那是什么?
What? What is it?
现在还不能告诉你
I can't tell you that now.
今晚肯尼迪大街 高地咖啡屋见
Meet me tomorrow at the Highland Café on Kennedy Avenue.
这不是陷阱 我会告诉你所有你想知道的
This isn't a trap. I will tell you everything you need to know.
高地咖啡屋  晚8点
Highland Café, eight pm.
好了  够了
All right. That's enough.
-我俩单独待会  -什么?
-Leave us alone.  -You sure?
离开这儿
Get out of here.
你没必要这么做
You don't have to do this.
你自找的
You brought it on yourself.
我只是一个传递痛苦的使者
I'm just an emissaryfor all the pain and suffering you caused.
所有被你毁了的家庭  还有那些孩子们
All the families you ruined. All the kids.
那吉米呢?
What about Jimmy?
他和这事毫无关系 你根本不需要杀他
He had nothing to do with this. You didn't need to kill him.
还有他那个英俊的儿子?
And what about his beautiful son?
那可是他的命根子啊
His whole life in front of him.
你竟然连孩子都不放过
Why did you need to kill a beautiful child?
在我做了那么多后 或许是我罪有应得
After all I've done, maybe I do deserve to die.
但你比我也好不了哪去
But you are no better than me.
我可以的  只要我想(变好)的话
But I can be. If I want.
上帝给了我选择的机会
God has given me the chance to choose.
或许我也应该给你一个机会
And maybe I should give you a chance as well.
什么都行  什么都行  求你了
You should. Anything. Anything. Please.
求你了
Please.
退出
Back out.
你指越狱?
Of the escape?
否则就去死
Or die.
我...
I wouldn't...
我也无法从这里离开
I wouldn't make it out there anyway.
从没想过出去
Not with my proclivities.
我要你发誓
I want you to give me your word.
你听见了么? 我要你发誓!
You hear me?I want you to give me your word!
好的  没问题  约翰  我答应你  答应你
You got it. You got it, John. You got it.
-求你了  -发誓
-Come on, you got it.  -Swear.
我退出  我发誓! 向上帝发誓!
I'm out, I swear.I swear to God.
我退出...
I swear...
好了  好了!
All right. All right!
我原谅你了 我原谅你了
I have forgiven you. I have forgiven you.
你还需要把刚才的话向耶稣说一遍
You just have to pray that the Lord Jesus Christ will do the same.
嘿  约翰  你知道么 其实  关于耶稣...
Hey, John. You know, actually, about Jesus...
能替我向他问好么?
Say hi to him for me, will you?
挖通了
I'm through.
-加把劲  -用力跺
-Keep it up.  -Come on. Stomp it.
警卫
Bulls.
你必须拦住他们 我们还没完事呢
You gotta stall 'em. We're not ready.
嘿  长官
Hey, boss.
你在这儿干什么  林肯?
What you doing out here?
歇会儿
aking a break.
去里面看看情况
I gotta check the status in there.
一切正常
It's all good.
那你更不用介意我去检查一下了
Then you won't mind me checking it out.
嘿
Hey. Hey!
你到底是怎么回事  伙计?
What the hell's your problem?
嘿  嘿! 给我让开  否则关你禁闭!
Hey, hey!Step off or you're going to the SHU.
放开他!
Burrows! Get off him!
多谢
Thanks.
好了...
Well,
咱们今晚就离开这儿
we leave tonight.
我哥哥呢?
Where's my brother?
迈克尔  有大麻烦了
Michael,we got a big problem.